Rino Indra Wicaksono

♥ Depok, West Java, Indonesia</

SUMMARY

An expected graduate in Computer Systems who wants to gain experience and has a strong interest in programming. I work well under pressure, can manage and complete tasks within deadlines, and possess strong verbal communication skills.

EXPERIENCE

Mobile Development Mentor - Bangkit Academy 2024 Batch 1

Bangkit Academy led by Google, Tokopedia, Gojek, & Traveloka

February 2024 - July 2024

- Provided guidance and mentoring in Mobile Application Development.
- Evaluate projects and provide constructive feedback to improve the quality of student work.
- · Supervise participants in developing their final project, offering direction and technical support to meet graduation standards.

Mobile Development Student

Bangkit Academy led by Google, Tokopedia, Gojek, & Traveloka

February 2023 - July 2023

- · Learning solid Programming Language.
- · Mastering to develop Mobile App from Beginner to Expert.
- · Create UI/UX Design with Figma and Adobe Illustrator.

Competition Participants

World Robot Games 2022 Thailand Championship

December 2022 - December 2022

- · Competed in The SumoOpen Category Representing Universitas Gunadarma And Indonesia.
- · Managed to get Third Runners Up and Performance Award Medal as a team.

Robotics Engineer Intern

PT SARI Teknologi

September 2022 - December 2022

- $\cdot \ \text{Mastering Programming Language for Robotics and Website, exp Arduino and PHP.}$
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Learn to operate Robots for Education and Industry.
- · Learn to collaborate with a team.

PROJECTS

Automatic Sorting Trash Bin With Internet Of Things Based Notification Using Solar Energy Source

Funding Recipients of Student Creativity Program (PKM) Karsa Cipta Scheme

- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Responsible for the sensor program and software.
- Create website and mobile application for Internet of Things notification.
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Responsible for creating and maintaining a database to store sensor data.

Doctor Plant App

Bangkit Academy led by Google, Tokopedia, Gojek, & Traveloka · April 2023 - June 2023

- $\cdot \ \text{Created an agricultural innovation app designed to scan crops and provide effective solutions}.$
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Developed a native Android app called Doctor Plant from scratch with Kotlin.
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Ensure the application runs smoothly without bugs by creating high quality and clean code.

Message Website Using React and Firebase

- · Developed and launched a messaging website using React and Firebase.
- · Create views and designs from the authentication page to the live chat page.
- · Created the entire database used for authentication and messaging.

EDUCATION

Expected Graduate in Computer Systems

Gunadarma University · Depok, Indonesia · 2024 · 3.76

High School Diploma In Natural Science

SMAN 55 Jakarta • DKI Jakarta • 2020

CERTIFICATIONS

React - The Complete Guide 2023

Udemy · 2023

Mobile Development From Beginner To Expert

Dicoding Indonesia · 2023

· Related To Bangkit Academy

Learn SOLID Programming Principles

Dicoding Indonesia · 2023

· Related To Bangkit Academy

UI/UX Design

Dicoding Indonesia · 2023

JavaScript Programming Language Fundamental

Gunadarma University Computerization Development Institute • 2023

FrontEnd Web

Dicoding Indonesia · 2022

ORGANIZATION

Head of Public Relations Division

Gunadarma University · Himpunan Mahasiswa Sistem Komputer · December 2022 - December 2023

- Create an aspiration platform for students in the computer systems department.
- · Encouraging students to participate in community service activities and providing resources for engagement.
- Become the contact person for the association when running organizational projects.

Staff Of Media And Creative

Gunadarma University • Himpunan Mahasiswa Sistem Komputer • December 2021 - December 2022

- · Responsible for design, documentation and publication in the Organization.
- · Create a Poster Design for Organizational Events.
- Became a copywriter and video editor at the Organization.

Member Google DSC

Gunadarma University · Google Developer Student Clubs · December 2022 - December 2023

- · Attended a seminar and talk show held by Google Developer Student Clubs, Gunadarma University.
- · Participated in an event organized by Google Developer Student Clubs, Gunadarma University.
- · Follow the news on the social media platform Google Developer Student Clubs, Gunadarma University.

SKILLS

Mobile Development: Android Native, Flutter

Frontend: React.js, Next.js

Programming Language: Python, Kotlin, JavaScript, Arduino, Ruby, HTML, CSS, PHP

Editing: Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Premiere Pro

Achievements: Third Runners Up And Performance Award In World Robot Games 2022